<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1 | OpenCENIA</title><link>https://opencenia.github.io/publication-type/1/</link><atom:link href="https://opencenia.github.io/publication-type/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>1</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://opencenia.github.io/media/logo_huadb352de640ebaad14838e8a393df198_92131_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>1</title><link>https://opencenia.github.io/publication-type/1/</link></image><item><title>ALBETO and DistilBETO: Lightweight Spanish Language Models</title><link>https://opencenia.github.io/models/canete-albeto-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opencenia.github.io/models/canete-albeto-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>In recent years there have been considerable advances in pre-trained language models, where non-English language versions have also been made available. Due to their increasing use, many lightweight versions of these models (with reduced parameters) have also been released to speed up training and inference times. However, versions of these lighter models (e.g., ALBERT, DistilBERT) for languages other than English are still scarce. In this paper we present ALBETO and DistilBETO, which are versions of ALBERT and DistilBERT pre-trained exclusively on Spanish corpora. We train several versions of ALBETO ranging from 5M to 223M parameters and one of DistilBETO with 67M parameters. We evaluate our models in the GLUES benchmark that includes various natural language understanding tasks in Spanish. The results show that our lightweight models achieve competitive results to those of BETO (Spanish-BERT) despite having fewer parameters. More specifically, our larger ALBETO model outperforms all other models on the MLDoc, PAWS-X, XNLI, MLQA, SQAC and XQuAD datasets. However, BETO remains unbeaten for POS and NER. As a further contribution, all models are publicly available to the community for future research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evaluation Benchmarks for Spanish Sentence Representations</title><link>https://opencenia.github.io/benchmarks/araujo-evaluation-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opencenia.github.io/benchmarks/araujo-evaluation-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spanish Pre-Trained BERT Model and Evaluation Data</title><link>https://opencenia.github.io/models/canete-cfp-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opencenia.github.io/models/canete-cfp-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Spanish language is one of the top 5 spoken languages in the world. Nevertheless, finding resources to train or evaluate Spanish language models is not an easy task. In this paper we help bridge this gap by presenting a BERT-based language model pre-trained exclusively on Spanish data. As a second contribution, we also compiled several tasks specifically for the Spanish language in a single repository much in the spirit of the GLUE benchmark. By fine-tuning our pre-trained Spanish model we obtain better results compared to other BERT-based models pre-trained on multilingual corpora for most of the tasks, even achieving a new state-of-the-art on some of them. We have publicly released our model, the pre-training data and the compilation of the Spanish benchmarks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spanish Word Embeddings</title><link>https://opencenia.github.io/models/perez-word-embeddings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opencenia.github.io/models/perez-word-embeddings/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An example conference paper</title><link>https://opencenia.github.io/publication/conference-paper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opencenia.github.io/publication/conference-paper/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Click the &lt;em>Cite&lt;/em> button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">code and math&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>